Tumo Masire, FullStack Developer

tumomasire@gmail.com

(Current) City: Cape Town, South Africa Mobile: +27 072 085 7781

Github: <u>www.github.com/TumoM</u> LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/tumo-masire-11206071</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A human-oriented **Software and Full-Stack Web Developer** with over 4 years of programming experience and 3 loves: problem solving and logical thinking, breaking things down, and building things up! A lifelong learner that is always looking to improve and grow themselves through online learning and experience, while contributing and helping others where he can. I have a passion for technology, data science, and Africa's future potential to contribute in these spaces!

Professional Skills and Interests:

- Software Engineering and Development
- Frontend & Backend Development
- Data Science and Data Analytics

- RESTful APIs and Web Scrapping
- Database Administration
- Deployment and Build Automation

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Social Science in Economics and Computer Science.

University of Cape Town (Cape Town, South Africa), Feb. 2018 – Jan. 2021

- Gold UCT Plus Award, Leadership Track 2020
- Notable Course Work: Data Structures and Algorithms 1 and 2, Computer Architecture, Databases,
 Operating Systems 1 & 2, Systems Analysis, Systems Design & Development, Electronic Commerce,
 Mobile Application Development, Study Design & Data Analysis for Scientists, Game Theory.
- Class Representative for 10 Courses MAM1010, MAM1008, POL1004, CSC1015, INF1002, INF2007, INF2009, ECO2003, ECO3020, ECO3021

GCE A-Levels (CIE Exam Board).

St Johns College (Johannesburg, South Africa), Feb. 2016 - Nov. 2017

- Gold Presidents Award 2017. The Duke of Edinburgh Award
- The Vita Award 2017. Awarded for the most extracurricular contribution in the cohort
- Level 3 First Aid Certification and First Aid Half-Colors 2017

Additional Training (Personal):

- Foundations of data science, Microsoft, Microsoft Learn Feb 2021
- Software Development Engineer Learning Path, AWS, AWS Educate Aug 2020
- The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery, Andrei Neagoie, Udemy Jan 2020
- Machine Learning, Stanford, Coursera Feb 2019
- Google IT Support Professional Certificate, a 5-course specialization, Google, Coursera Feb 2019

PROFESSIONAL AND WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Cape Town (Part-Time)

Feb 2019 – Jun. 2020, Feb 2021 – Jun 2020

University Computer Science Tutor (2019-20, 2021) and Hotseat Tutor (Feb. 2020 – Jun. 2020)

- Assisted students with logical thinking and with debugging code for assignments.
- Working in a Linux environment to compile and mark student code.
- Invigilated and Marked student tests and assignments to help the course progress.

Botswana Presidential Covid Task Force (Internship)

Dec. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Software Engineer

Rapid application development to meet the needs of the Presidential Covid Task Force.

• Used React to create an interactive "Movement" visualization map from an input Excel File

- Ported React Movement application to Electron and created cross-platform builds using Travis-Ci builds
- Prototyped a **Python** web automation tool to process movement permit requests given a list if ID's
- Converted Python automation tool to **Java** to read ID excel files from and email, and a **JavaFX** interface to display the results of the permit processing.

ITohro (*Contract*)

Jun. 2020 - Sep. 2020

Full Stack Developer

A React App platform that facilitates the sales of services directly between consumers and service providers in South Africa.

- Worked with CSS, HTML, and JavaScript to create and edit React Frontend components and pages.
- Used **Nodejs** to create backend systems to enable features such as authenticated login, location services, and email notifications.
- Implemented admin dashboard to provide sales information and order tracking.

Construct Education (Fulltime then Part-time)

Jun. 2019 then Jul. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Learning Technologist

An education delivery company working with Schools and Organizations to digitize course content onto LMS'

- Worked with **HTML**, **CSS**, and **JavaScript** to translate client requirements into responsive pages on LMS Platforms.
- Utilized JavaScript and Custom Python grading scripts to create advanced problem types.
- Flexibly worked across a variety of LMSs and environmental constraints (Blackboard, Canvas, EdX).

Zaio (Part-Time)

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019 & Aug. 2019 - Oct. 2019

Backend Software Developer

A Web Development house that freelances projects to young developers.

- Created cart and payment processing backends using Payfast and PeachPay in Nodejs.
- Structured database schemas and implemented both MySQL and Mongo Databases.
- Collaborated with frontend and backend developers on projects using version control **GitHub** and **GitLab**.

LEADERSHIP AND STUDENT LIFE

- Humanities Student Council, Academic Chair for the Social Sciences – Mar. 2020 to Oct. 2020
- Humanities Student Council, Public
 Relations Officer Nov. 2019 to Mar. 2020
- Student Parliament, voting member 2020

- Senate, voting member 2020
- International Students Forum (ISF), acting Secretary – 2020/21
- Undergraduate Academic Sub-Council (UASC) – 2020
- Developers Society, Secretary 2019/20

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Rona Tracker SA: Personal Project. A responsive Full-Stack website that tracks Covid-19 Statistics in South Africa, and on a provincial level. Uses web scrapping to gather the statistics. Built using Node.js, EJS as a templating engine, Semantic UI, SCSS, and Postgres DB (AWS). Deployed to Heroku. (Apr. 2020)
Learn Python Catalogue: Capstone Project. Team Lead and Lead Programmer. A site that allows users to upload Python resources using a link, and the information is scrapped and stored. Uses React, TypeScript,

Express, MongoDB. Predominantly did backend work but also helped on frontend (Aug 2020 - Oct. 2020)

OTHER RELEVANT INFORMATION

Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, MySQL, Postgres, Mongo DB, R, Android (Java), SCSS **Frameworks & Libraries**: Node.js, Express.js, React, GraphQL, Ionic, Bootstrap, Flask, Selenium, JavaFx,

Electron

Tools: Postman, Jenkins/Travis-Cl, JetBrains, VS Code, Linux, Windows, GitHub + Gitlab, Heroku, AWS, Docker